Inventory of the Jude Wanniski papers, 1965-2006
Hoover Institution Archives
Jude Wanniski papers,
1965-2005
2008C50
Wanniski, Jude, 1936-
30 manuscript boxes (12 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Acquired in 2008, the Jude Wanniski papers in the Hoover Institution Archives document the career of a journalist and consultant who, from the early 1970s until his death in 2005, sought to influence both popular opinion and the political establishment in the United States. As an editor of the Wall Street Journal, and then as the head of his own consulting firm, Polyconomics, Inc., Wanniski was a tireless advocate of supply-side economics, a term that he devised after becoming acquainted with the ideas of the economists Arthur Laffer and Robert Mundell. In opposition to Keynesian doctrine, Wanniski and other supply-siders promoted tax reductions and a reduced role for government as means of promoting capital formation and economic growth.
Administrative Information
Access
Box 30 is closed. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1936 Born, Pottstown, Pennsylvania
1959 Master of Arts, Journalism, University of California at Los Angeles
1961-1965 Columnist, Las Vegas Review-Journal
1965-1972 Columnist, National Observer
1972-1978 Associate editor, Wall Street Journal
1975 Coins term "supply-side economics" and popularizes ideas of Arthur Laffer and Robert Mundell
1978 Author, The Way the World Works
1978-2005 President, Polyconomics, Inc.
1998 Author, The Last Race of the 20th Century
2005 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 2008, the Jude Wanniski papers in the Hoover Institution Archives document the career of a journalist and consultant who, from the early 1970s until his death in 2005, sought to influence both popular opinion and the political establishment in the United States. As an editor of the Wall Street Journal, and then as the head of his own consulting firm, Polyconomics, Inc., Wanniski was a tireless advocate of supply-side economics, a term that he devised after becoming acquainted with the ideas of the economists Arthur Laffer and Robert Mundell. In opposition to Keynesian doctrine, Wanniski and other supply-siders promoted tax reductions and a reduced role for government as means of promoting capital formation and economic growth.
In 1978, Wanniski published a book on economics, The Way the World Works, that popularized these ideas and gave a supply-side account of history. He wrote many editorials on public policy and conducted an extensive correspondence with politicians whom he hoped would implement the ideas he championed, often functioning as an unofficial campaign adviser. Among those he advised were Jack Kemp, Bob Dole, and Ronald Reagan, as well as two businessmen who ran for the presidency, Ross Perot and Steve Forbes. Although primarily associated with the Republican Party, Wanniski also had a close connection to the Democrats Bill Bradley and Charles Rangel, and corresponded with President Bill Clinton.
The Correspondence series forms the bulk of the Wanniski papers. Routine correspondence is organized chronologically, followed by more significant correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name. Along with the political figures already mentioned, there are significant exchanges of letters between Wanniski and various policymakers and officials, including Alan Greenspan, Paul Volcker, Donald Rumsfeld, and James Baker. This series also includes Wanniski's substantial correspondence with the Nation of Islam leader, Louis Farrakhan. Wanniski's association with Farrakhan, whom he came to view as a friend and political ally, proved to be highly controversial.
There is also an Email messages series in the papers. Dating from late in Wanniski's career, a number of these messages are available as searchable PDF files that can be viewed on a workstation computer in the reading room. There are also printouts of some messages in the papers themselves. In both cases, certain recipients are identified only by email address and salutation rather than full name.
The Political consulting file in the papers is comprised of memoranda sent to Bob Dole and Jack Kemp, as well as a number of speeches written by Wanniski for others. The Speeches and writings series includes the manuscripts of his books, The Way the World Works and The Last Race of the 20th Century, as well as numerous examples of Wanniski's work as a journalist and his record as a public speaker. In addition to numerous pieces on economics, there are also many speeches and writings devoted to issues of foreign policy. By the end of his life, Wanniski had become a sharp critic of American military intervention in Iraq and elsewhere.
Wanniski's professional life is documented in the Subject file of the papers, which includes materials relating to his work as a consultant in Puerto Rico and the Russian Federation.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into seven series: Biographical file, Correspondence, Email Messages, Speeches and Writings, Political Consulting file, Writings by Others and Subject file.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
United States--Economic policy.; United States--Politics and government.
Collection Contents
- Biographical file, 1982-1997 (Box 1:)
  Contains biography, clippings, conference program, and curriculum vitae, arranged by physical form
  - Biography, 1995 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Clippings, 1979-1995 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Conference program, with autographs of participants, 1982 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1997 (Folder 1: 4)
- Correspondence, 1965-2001 (Box 1-19:)
  Contains letters, memoranda, and enclosures, with a general file, arranged chronologically, and an alphabetical file, arranged by name of correspondent
  - General, 1965-2000
    - 1965-1968 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1969-1973 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1974-1977 (Folder 1: 7)
    - 1978 (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1979 (Folder 1: 9-10)
    - 1980 (Folder 1: 11-12)
    - 1981 (Folder 2: 1-6)
    - 1982 (Folder 2: 7-11)
    - 1983 (Folder 3: 1-3)
    - 1984 (Folder 3: 4-6)
    - 1985 (Folder 3: 7-10)
    - 1986 (Folder 4: 1-3)
    - 1987 (Folder 4: 4-5)
    - 1988 (Folder 4: 6-7)
    - 1989 (Folder 4: 8-10, Folder 5: 1)
    - 1990 (Folder 5: 2-5)
    - 1991 (Folder 5: 6-10, Folder 6: 1-2)
    - 1992 (Folder 6: 3-6)
    - 1993 (Folder 6: 7-10, Folder 7: 1-2)
    - 1994 (Folder 7: 3-6)
    - 1995 (Folder 7: 7-10, Folder 8: 1-3)
    - 1996 (Folder 8: 4-10)
    - 1996 (Folder 9: 1)
    - 1997 (Folder 9: 2-9)
    - 1998 (Folder 10: 1-3)
    - 1999 (Folder 10: 4)
    - 2000 (Folder 10: 5)
    - Adelman, Kenneth L., 1986 (Folder 10: 6)
    - Agee, William, 1980-1990 (Folder 10: 7)
    - Allen, Richard V., 1980-1981 (Folder 10: 8)
    - Ames, Eugene L., Jr., 1984-1986 (Folder 10: 9)
    - Anderson, Martin, 1979-1981 (Folder 10: 10)
    - Angell, Wayne, 1990-1997 (Folder 10: 11)
    - Apple, R. W., Jr., 1995-1997 (Folder 10: 12)
    - Aspe, Pedro, 1990-1997 (Folder 10: 13)
    - Augustine, Norman, 1988-1989 (Folder 10: 14)
    - Ayittey, George B. N., 1993-1996 (Folder 10: 15)
    - Baker, Howard, Jr., 1987 (Folder 10: 16)
    - Baker, James A., III, 1981-1996
      - 1981-1986 (Folder 11: 1)
      - 1987-1996 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Bartley, Robert, 1975-1997
      - 1975-1994 (Folder 11: 3)
      - 1995-1997 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Benko, Ralph, 1981-1988 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Bennett, Robert F., 1994-1999 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Berrocal, José M., 1985-1992 (Folder 11: 7)
    - Blustein, Paul, 1984 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Bodman, Richard S., 1992 (Folder 11: 9)
    - Bork, Robert H., 1988 (Folder 11: 10)
    - Boskin, Michael J., 1989-1991 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Bradley, Bill, 1982-1996 (Folder 11: 12)
    - Brady, Nicholas F., 1988-1991 (Folder 11: 13)
    - Brenner, Reuven, 1992-2000
      - 1992-1993 (Folder 11: 14)
      - 1994-2000 (Folder 11: 15)
    - Brittan, Samuel, 1980-1982 (Folder 12: 1)
    - Brown, Jerry, 1991-1992 (Folder 12: 2)
    - Buchanan, Patrick J., 1974-1999 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Buckley, William F., 1980-1997 (Folder 12: 4)
    - Bucy, J. Fred, Jr., 1978-1985 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Bush, George H. W., 1981-1991 (Folder 12: 6)
    - Bush, George W., 1988 (Folder 12: 7)
    - Carrión, Richard, 1979-1993 (Folder 12: 8)
    - Casey, William J., 1981-1985 (Folder 12: 9)
    - Cheney, Richard B., 1978-2000 (Folder 12: 10)
    - Chiang, William, 1983-1984 (Folder 12: 11)
    - Clinton, Bill, 1995-1997 (Folder 12: 12)
    - Colorado, Antonio J., 1985 (Folder 12: 13)
    - Connally, John, 1975 (Folder 12: 14)
    - Cowan, Ed, 1979-1980 (Folder 12: 15)
    - Crane, Edward H. (Folder 12: 16)
    - Cuomo, Mario, 1987-1997 (Folder 12: 17)
    - Dannemeyer, William E., 1981-1989 (Folder 12: 18)
    - Darman, Richard G., 1984-1992
      - 1984-1988 (Folder 12: 19)
      - 1989-1992 (Folder 12: 20)
    - Diaz Saldaña, Manuel, 1993 (Folder 12: 21)
    - Dole, Bob, 1971-1996
      - 1971-1989 (Folder 13: 1)
      - 1993 (Folder 13: 2-3)
      - 1994 (Folder 13: 4-5)
      - 1995-1996 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Dowd, Maureen, 1987-1997 (Folder 13: 7)
    - Farrakhan, Louis, 1996-2001 (Folder 13: 8)
    - Foote, Ashby M., 1991 (Folder 13: 9)
    - Forbes, Steve, 1987-1997
      - 1987-1994 (Folder 13: 10)
      - 1995 (Folder 13: 11)
      - 1996-1997 (Folder 13: 12)
    - Fossedal, Gregory A., 1982-1983 (Folder 14: 1)
    - Foxman, Abraham H., 1997-1998 (Folder 14: 2)
    - Frank, Barney, 1997-2000 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Frankel, Max, 1977-1999 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Friedman, Thomas, 1994-1997 (Folder 14: 5)
    - Gaidar, Yegor, 1991-1992 (Folder 14: 6)
    - Genetski, Robert J., 1982 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Gergen, David, 1981-1993 (Folder 14: 8)
    - Gigot, Paul, 1996 (Folder 14: 9)
    - Gil Díaz, Francisco, 1995 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Gingrich, Newt, 1979-1997 (Folder 14: 11)
    - Glaubert, Robert, 1989 (Folder 14: 12)
    - Goldman, David, 1991 (Folder 14: 13)
    - Gore, Al, 1996-1997 (Folder 14: 14)
    - Government Development Bank for Puerto Rico, 1985-1986 (Folder 14: 15)
    - Gramm, Phil, 1993-1994 (Folder 14: 16)
    - Grannis, Scott F., 1994-1995 (Folder 14: 17)
    - Gray, Arthur, Jr., 1991-1997 (Folder 14: 18)
    - Greener, William, 1979-1987 (Folder 14: 19)
    - Greenspan, Alan, 1991-1997
      - 1991-1993 (Folder 14: 20)
      - 1994 (Folder 14: 21)
      - 1995-1997 (Folder 14: 22)
    - Hannaford, Peter D., 1976-1995 (Folder 15: 1)
    - Hilliard, C. Paul, 1983-1992 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Hodges, Luther H., Jr., 1979-1980 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Holbrooke, Richard, 1998 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Iklé, Fred C., 1983-1998 (Folder 15: 5)
    - Jackson, Jesse, 1992 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Jaffe, Herbert, 1997 (Folder 15: 7)
    - Joseph, Keith, 1979 (Folder 15: 8)
    - Judis, John B., 1992-1996 (Folder 15: 9)
    - Kemp, Jack, 1976-1999
      - 1976-1989 (Folder 15: 10)
      - 1990-1995 (Folder 15: 11)
      - 1996 (Folder 15: 12)
      - 1997-1999 (Folder 15: 13)
    - Kilborn, Peter, 1984-1985 (Folder 15: 14)
    - Kimura, Yorizo, 1989-1994 (Folder 15: 15)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1993-1996 (Folder 15: 16)
    - Knowles, Ruth Sheldon, 1979 (Folder 15: 17)
    - Koch, Edward I., 1990-1997 (Folder 15: 18)
    - Kondracke, Morton, 1981 (Folder 15: 19)
    - Kovach, Bill, 1986 (Folder 16: 1)
    - Kristol, Irving, 1977-1995 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Kristol, William, 1989-1994 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Krugman, Paul, 2000 (Folder 16: 4)
    - Laffer, Arthur B., 1977-1998 (Folder 16: 5)
    - Lapham, Lewis, 1979 (Folder 16: 6)
    - Larsen, Wendell, 1979-1990 (Folder 16: 7)
    - Laxalt, Paul, 1981-1984 (Folder 16: 8)
    - Lehrman, Lewis E., 1979-1986 (Folder 16: 9)
    - Lewis, Anthony, 1980-1998 (Folder 16: 10)
    - Lewis, Flora, 1983 (Folder 16: 11)
    - Lindsey, Lawrence, 1994 (Folder 16: 12)
    - Lott, Trent, 1982-1997 (Folder 16: 13)
    - Lueck, Bruce C., 1994-1996 (Folder 16: 14)
    - Lugar, Richard G., 1980-1985 (Folder 16: 15)
    - MacAvoy, Paul W., 1982 (Folder 16: 16)
    - Markossov, Gueorgui, 1990-1994 (Folder 16: 17)
    - Martin, Preston, 1984-1985 (Folder 16: 18)
    - McCain, John, 1996-1997 (Folder 16: 19)
    - McDougall, George, 1979-1980 (Folder 16: 20)
    - Meese, Edwin, 1980-1986 (Folder 16: 21)
    - Meltzer, Allan H., 1995 (Folder 16: 22)
    - Mfume, Kweisi, 1994-1999 (Folder 16: 23)
    - Miles, Stephen B., 1982 (Folder 16: 24)
    - Milken, Michael, 1989-1997 (Folder 16: 25)
    - Moore, John, 1991-1995 (Folder 16: 26)
    - Moreira, Marcílio Marques, 1987-1991 (Folder 16: 27)
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1993 (Folder 16: 28)
    - Mundell, Robert, 1978-1988 (Folder 16: 29)
    - Mundell, William, 1990-1992 (Folder 16: 30)
    - Murray, Alan, 1996 (Folder 16: 31)
    - Neureiter, Norman, 1982-1988 (Folder 16: 32)
    - New York Times, 1979-1998 (Folder 16: 33)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1983-1993 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Norris, Floyd, 1989-1997 (Folder 17: 2)
    - Nygaard, James L., 1978-1979 (Folder 17: 3)
    - Oyola, José Ramón, 1985 (Folder 17: 4)
    - Packwood, Robert, 1968-1996 (Folder 17: 5)
    - Passell, Peter, 1979-1992 (Folder 17: 6)
    - Paul, Ron, 1981 (Folder 17: 7)
    - Pennant-Rea, Rupert, 1990 (Folder 17: 8)
    - Perle, Richard, 1985 (Folder 17: 9)
    - Perot, H. Ross, 1992-1996 (Folder 17: 10)
    - Petty, George S., 1989-1997 (Folder 17: 11)
    - Pietrantoni Blasini, Julio, 1979-1982 (Folder 17: 12)
    - Pietri, Ivar A., 1981-1993 (Folder 17: 13)
    - Podhoretz, Norman, 1990-1993 (Folder 17: 14)
    - Powell, Colin, 1995-1997 (Folder 17: 15)
    - Pownall, Thomas G., 1979-1991 (Folder 17: 16)
    - Proxmire, William, 1979-1985 (Folder 17: 17)
    - Quayle, Dan, 1989-1999 (Folder 17: 18)
    - Rangel, Charles, 1990-1999 (Folder 17: 19)
    - Rattner, Steven, 1980-1983 (Folder 17: 20)
    - Reagan, Ronald, 1976-1988 (Folder 17: 21)
    - Reed, John S., 1987-1989 (Folder 17: 22)
    - Regan, Donald, 1981-1987 (Folder 17: 23)
    - Regnery, Alfred S., 1997 (Folder 17: 24)
    - Reynolds, Alan, 1975-1979 (Folder 17: 25)
    - Rich, Frank, 1995-1997 (Folder 17: 26)
    - Richards, Ann W., 1992 (Folder 17: 27)
    - Riegle, Donald W., 1985-1994 (Folder 17: 28)
    - Romero-Barceló, Carlos, 1977-1984 (Folder 18: 1)
    - Rosenthal, A. M., 1979-1998 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Rosselló, Pedro, 1993 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Rubin, Robert E., 1992-1995 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Rumsfeld, Donald, 1968-1996
      - 1968-1980 (Folder 18: 5)
      - 1981-1996 (Folder 18: 6)
    - Russert, Tim, 1997 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Ryan, Jay, 1995 (Folder 18: 8)
    - Ryskind, Allan, 1978-1987 (Folder 18: 9)
    - Safir, Andrew, 1979 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Safire, William, 1978-1996 (Folder 18: 11)
    - Salinas de Gortari, Carlos, 1991-1992 (Folder 18: 12)
    - Samuelson, Robert, 1981-1991 (Folder 18: 13)
    - Sanger, David, 1996-1998 (Folder 18: 14)
    - Seaga, Edward, 1985 (Folder 18: 15)
    - Sears, John, 1979-1980 (Folder 18: 16)
    - Schmertz, Herbert, 1985-1987 (Folder 18: 17)
    - Seligman, Daniel, 1979-1987 (Folder 18: 18)
    - Shapiro, Rob, 1992 (Folder 18: 19)
    - Shipman, Stephen W., 1996 (Folder 18: 20)
    - Shultz, George P., 1982-1991 (Folder 18: 21)
    - Silk, Leonard, 1980-1990 (Folder 18: 22)
    - Silverglate, Harvey A., 1992 (Folder 18: 23)
    - Simon, William E., 1979-1980 (Folder 18: 24)
    - Singer, S. Fred, 1981 (Folder 18: 25)
    - Smith, Hedrick, 1984-1985 (Folder 19: 1)
    - Smith, R. Arnold, 1992 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Smith Richardson Foundation, Inc., 1976 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, 1997 (Folder 19: 4)
    - St. Onge, Arthur, 1980 (Folder 19: 5)
    - Stein, Herbert, 1981-1982 (Folder 19: 6)
    - Stockman, David A., 1979-1982 (Folder 19: 7)
    - Strauss, Robert, 1991-1994 (Folder 19: 8)
    - Suarez Mier, Manuel, 1989-1990 (Folder 19: 9)
    - Sununu, John, 1989-1991 (Folder 19: 10)
    - Tolley, James L., 1985-1987 (Folder 19: 11)
    - Tómasson, Gunnar, 1984-1998 (Folder 19: 12)
    - Torricelli, Robert, 1993-1998 (Folder 19: 13)
    - Turgeon, Lynn, 1981 (Folder 19: 14)
    - Uchitelle, Louis, 1989-1999 (Folder 19: 15)
    - Verney, Russ, 1996 (Folder 19: 16)
    - Volcker, Paul A., 1979-1995 (Folder 19: 17)
    - Wallich, Henry C., 1983 (Folder 19: 18)
    - Wallop, Malcolm, 1986-1996 (Folder 19: 19)
    - Wanniski, Terry, 1994 (Folder 19: 20)
    - Weiss, William L., 1988 (Folder 19: 21)
    - Weyrich, Paul, 1985 (Folder 19: 22)
    - Whitman, Christine Todd, 1990-1993 (Folder 19: 23)
    - Wicker, Tom, 1982 (Folder 19: 24)
    - Will, George, 1990-1996 (Folder 19: 25)
    - Williams, Armstrong, 1993 (Folder 19: 26)
    - Williamson, Richard S., 1983-1986 (Folder 19: 27)
    - Wilson, Margaret Bush, 1978-1992 (Folder 19: 28)
    - Wilson, Pete, 1989 (Folder 19: 29)
    - Yeutter, Clayton, 1988-1992 (Folder 19: 30)
    - Zoellick, Robert, 1988-1992 (Folder 19: 31)
- Email messages, 1996-2005
  Contains printed email messages, arranged chronologically. Use copies of some digital files available on workstation computer in Reading Room. Data from compact discs contains electronic email messages of jwanniski@polyconomics.com account
  - Files from one compact disc containing messages, 1996-1999 June (Folder Reading Room)
    Includes In, Out, and Trash mailboxes, but the three types of boxes are not identified and separated. Much of the data is formatted and readable, but much is also unformatted, garbled and unreadable. Provided as searchable PDF files ranging from about 300 to 700 pages, available on work station in Reading Room. These messages were recovered by a data recovery service and saved to a CD on 1999 June 15, prior to acquisition by Hoover. Consists of 47 files with sequential filenames, ASC00000 to ASC00046
  - Files from one compact disc containing messages, 2002-2005 (Folder Reading Room)
    Includes several versions of the In box and Out box, one Trash box, one GPrather 2004 box, one James Galbraith folder, and a folder of received attachments. Provided as searchable PDF files, some exceeding 10,000 pages, available on work station in Reading Room. These electronic email messages have some overlap with the printed email messages
  - Printed email messages of jwanniski@polyconomics.com account, 1999-2005
    - Messages sent and received, printed for Barbara Haslam, 1999 (Folder 20: 1)
    - Messages sent and received, printed for Paula Hocking, 2000-2005
      - 2000 (Folder 20: 2)
      - 2001 (Folder 20: 3-5)
      - 2002 (Folder 20: 6-7)
      - 2003 (Folder 20: 8)
      - 2004 (Folder 20: 9-10)
      - 2005 (Folder 20: 11)
    - Messages sent and received, 2004-2005
      Printed in 2006, prior to acquisition by Hoover
      - Sent (Out box), 2004-2005
        - General, 2004-2005
          - 2004
            - January (Folder 21: 1)
            - February (Folder 21: 2)
            - March (Folder 21: 3)
            - April (Folder 21: 4)
            - May (Folder 21: 5)
            - June (Folder 21: 6)
            - July (Folder 21: 7)
            - August (Folder 21: 8)
            - September (Folder 21: 9)
            - October (Folder 21: 10)
            - November (Folder 22: 1)
            - December (Folder 22: 2)
          - 2005
            - January (Folder 22: 3)
            - August (Folder 22: 4)
        - To Ben Bernanke, 2004-2005 (Folder 22: 5)
        - To Karl Rove, 2004-2005 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Received (In box), 2004-2005
        - 2004 (Folder 22: 7-11, Folder 23: 1-2)
        - 2005 (Folder 23: 3)
- Speeches and Writings, 1974-2005; 23-27
  Contains articles, monographs, and speeches, largely relating to economics, American politics, and foreign affairs
  - With Robert L. Bartley, "The Limits of the Press Corps in a Political/Technical Debate," paper, Conference on Expert Advice and Public Choice, Racine, Wisconsin, 1974 April 4-6 (Folder 23: 4)
  - "It's Time to Cut Taxes," Wall Street Journal, 1974 December 11 (Folder 23: 5)
  - "The Mundell-Laffer Hypothesis--A New View of the World Economy," The Public Interest, 1975 Spring
    - Proofs (Folder 23: 6)
    - Typescript (Folder 23: 7)
    - Printed copy (Folder 23: 8)
  - "A Bull Market Scenario,", 1978 (Folder 23: 9)
  - "An End to Inflation,", 1978 (Folder 23: 10)
  - The Way the World Works, 1978
    - Notes (Folder 23: 11)
    - Clippings (Folder 23: 12)
    - Monograph excerpts and reports (Folder 23: 13-15)
    - Typescript (Folder 24: 1-11, Folder 25: 1-3)
  - "Taxes, Revenues, and the 'Laffer Curve',", 1978 June (Folder 25: 4)
  - "The Way the World Works," speech, National Tax Reduction Seminar, Missouri Council for Economic Development, St. Louis, Missouri, 1978 July 28 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Article on balanced budget amendment, 1979 (Folder 25: 6)
  - Article on Jack Kemp, American Spectator, 1979 March (Folder 25: 7)
    Includes correspondence
  - Speech, American Stock Exchange, New York City, 1979 July (Folder 25: 8)
  - "Oil in Abundance,"Harper's, 1979 October (Folder 25: 9)
  - Article on energy, 1979 October 16 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Article on 1929 Wall Street crash, Wall Street Journal, 1979 October 29 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Speech, Energy Future: Policies and Consequences conference, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, 1980 February 21 (Folder 25: 12)
  - Speech on economics, Switzerland, 1980 June (Folder 25: 13)
  - Article on oil industry, 1980 June (Folder 25: 14)
  - Speech on supply-side economics, Consumer Credit Insurance Association meeting, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, 1981 June (Folder 25: 15)
  - "A Modern International Gold Standard: A Supply-Side View," Conference of the Banco Central del Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay, 1981 December 16-19 (Folder 25: 16)
  - "Inflation, Deflation and the Gold Constant," Ludwig von Mises lecture, Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan, 1982 April 20 (Folder 25: 17)
  - Article on stock market, 1982 June 15 (Folder 25: 18)
  - Testimony on a balanced budget amendment, House Judiciary Committee, Washington, D.C., 1982 August 4 (Folder 25: 19)
  - "Economic Impact of the '84 Elections,", 1984 (Folder 25: 20)
  - "A Gold Standard Q and A,", 1984 April 5 (Folder 25: 21)
  - "Gold, Oil and Economic Growth in the Decade Ahead," paper, Fifth Annual International Conference on Alaska's Resources, Anchorage, Alaska, 1985 February 14 (Folder 25: 22)
  - "The Philippine Election and Constitutional Crisis,", 1986 February 24 (Folder 26: 1)
  - Article on Ronald Reagan's economic program, 1986 November 11 (Folder 26: 2)
  - "To Aid the Poor, Cut Capital Gains Taxes," New York Times, 1989 July 25 (Folder 26: 3)
  - "Bradley's Team Gave the Market Its Drubbing," Wall Street Journal, 1989 October 19 (Folder 26: 4)
  - "Washington Locks the U.S. into Recession," Wall Street Journal (Folder 26: 5)
  - "To Ease Northeast Budget Strains...," New York Times, 1990 June 2 (Folder 26: 6)
  - "Dog Days: A Lot to Worry about,", 1990 August 3 (Folder 26: 7)
  - "Dismal Developments,", 1990 August 8 (Folder 26: 8)
  - "A Middle East Scenario,", 1990 August 28 (Folder 26: 9)
  - "Postpone the Floating of the Ruble,", 1991 (Folder 26: 10)
  - "Trial by Press: James B. Stewart vs. Michael Milken,", 1991 October 9